Previously. on "Good Sam"...
You're supervising
these doctors.
You're above them
in knowledge.
rank and skill.
Act like it.
I'm second in command here.
and he shows me no respect.
I think I'm gonna take
the Cleveland offer. Caleb.
It's not about me.
Yeah.
Dad!
My father can never be replaced.
but I vow to carry on
his legacy to the
best of my ability.
You've earned this.
And I say that as your
chief medical officer.
not your mother.
I'm Sam. by the way.
I'm Malcolm. Kingsley.
I'm the new director of finance.
Sam!
- Mom.
- It's your father.
He's waking up.
You were shot six months ago.
How long...
till I can work again?
You have
to be proctored.
I'll do it.
I'll supervise him.
What. do you have company?
And since you brought up Lex.
the next time you want to help
me. don't screw my best friend!
My dad is here.
- With my dad.
- The chairman of the board.
He's trying to go over my head.
skip to the end
of his proctorship.
You all asked me
to step in as chief.
And now my father is awake and
you are asking me to step aside.
And I can't do
that. Because I am
a better chief.
May the best Dr. Griffith win.
"Nowhere to Run" by Martha
Reeves & the Vandellas playing...
This man's appendix lasted
75 years before it blew.
We should all be so lucky.
Look at that ascending colon.
Dr. Tucker.Beautiful.
Thank
you to Elaine Hart
for her generous gift.
♪ Baby
♪ Nowhere to hide
Now. it
can only be one of you.
The other gets
to head down to the
lobby at the donor event.
Who wants the
appendectomy honors?
I want it. I want it. You
got to clip that aneurysm
- in neuro yesterday.
- While you assisted on a triple bypass.
Also. Sam's at that donor event.
Low blow.
Still true. You better go.
I'll do the appy. Fine by me.
Better hurry before
Malcolm beats you to it.
You look...
Like I'd rather be
wearing scrubs?
Not what I was gonna say.
Please welcome
Chairman of the Board
Byron Kingsley.
Please.
applaud yourselves.
Each of you make
Lakeshore what it is.
This is my first big
schmooze event
since I've been competing
with my dad for the chief position.
I have to impress the board.
Well. just be yourself and
pretend you're wearing scrubs.
That's terrible advice.
I don't get to cut any of
these people open.
Do you have a vision
for the department?
Do you believe that you
are the best person to run it?
I do.
Then tell them why.
Thank you
for your generous gifts.
All right. you ready?
What? No.
I was gonna work my
way up to your dad.
No. no. trust me...
Now's the time.
He's always in a good mood
after he gives a
speech. Come on.
Would you stop?
You look like a lion
hunting a gazelle.
I can't believe that Sam's
still going through with this.
There's no way
the board's gonna choose
her for chief over me.
She's starting a
war she can't win.
I know I can't talk either of
you out of this competition.
but she's my daughter.
Don't hurt her.
Hey.
She's my daughter. too.
It's the last thing I want.
Not with your cholesterol.
Oh. Your new husband know
you've still got a thing
about my cholesterol?
Go eat a vegetable.
All right. Dr. Shah.
we'll have this guy back on
the tennis court in no time.
Here I go.
Slow and steady.
What the hell?
I can't see anything.
He's hemorrhaging.
What did you do?
Uh. I don't know.
There was some
resistance. Maybe adhesions.
How can...
What can I do?
Converting to open. 10 blade.
Yes. Doctor.
Suction. Dr. Shah.
Large bore suction here.Yeah.
Set up another cell saver.
Over here.
There's no visualization.
It's coming too fast.
Over here. Over here.
Give me that clamp.
Activate massive
transfusion protocol.
I-I can't get source control.
The tissue's falling apart.
Move! Move!
We're losing him.
Call it.
Advertise your product or brand here
contact www.OpenSubtitles.org today
*GOOD SAM
Season 01  Episode 03
Episode Title: " Butt of the Joke"
Aired on: January 19. 2022.
Great speech. Dad.
Thank you. son. You
remember Dr. Griffith.
Thank you again for
considering me for the position.
I'm eager to see
how it all plays out.
I'm eager to tell you
about the innovations
I have planned
for my department.
Virtual and augmented reality
training tools enhance
performance and lower...
Put me back in a coma. Thought
this was a party.
Hey.
How you doing? Big man.
I got a tee time with
Waxie on Saturday.
You in? Waxman.
He may own two planes.
but his backswing has seven.
Well. if you're around tomorrow.
I would love to tell
you about my plans.
Oh. hey! You say hi to Gina?
No. I haven't. I need to.
Mm...
Outwitted by a golf joke.
Mm. a
golf joke about Waxman.
Our biggest donor.Yeah.
What is that?
Hmm? Oh.
That thing you're
doing with your fingers.
It's the. um.
chromatic scale.
I just need something to do
with my hands when I'm stressed.
What if you try this?
That help?
It does. actually.
I'm sorry to interrupt.
Uh...
We lost the patient.
In a routine lap appy?
Isan's taking it pretty hard.
His hands were in the body.
Please
record your message.
Isan. it's me.
Caleb told me what
happened. I'm so sorry. I...
If you need to talk. I'm
here. okay? Call me anytime.
You were always so competitive.
When we played Candy Land.
you were out for blood.
But...
you weren't great at losing.
The board sees me as a
contender. even if you don't.
I'm talking to you
as your father.
I'm trying to spare
you the humiliation.
What you should do
is back out gracefully.
before you get hurt.
I don't want to see
you lose the respect
of your colleagues
and the board.
No. you just want your job
back without having to fight for it.
If I have to... fight you.
I will. but...
Sam. it's gonna
end badly for you.
I disagree.
And I am not backing down.
Okay. So be it.
Consider yourself...
warned.
This is Tracy
Reynolds. 40 years old.
Chest pain. headache.
No family history
of heart disease.
It's not a heart attack.
I really don't have to be here.
Tracy. honey. if it hurts there.
you come here. Right. Doctors?
That is right. Tracy.
hi. I'm Dr. Griffith.
We're gonna start
you with an EKG.
Thank you.
Maybe-maybe
one of my implants ruptured?
Those aren't real?
Uh. B-Baldwin
and-and I are new...
Dating apps.
No stigma anymore.Mm.
Last night was our
first time together.
Yeah. And
it'd been a while.
Things... Mm-hmm.
Things got a little
intense.
Mm-hmm.Okay. We got it.
We'll check it out.Okay.
Oh. and. uh. also. one of...
One of my knees hurts.
Next time we'll
stretch out first.
Yeah.
What?
Large inferior Q waves.
Tracy. have you ever seen a
doctor for chest pain before?
Yeah. Once. a f-few years ago.
He said it was anxiety.
I'm guessing he
didn't do an EKG.
This is showing us that you've
had a heart attack before.
How can I have had a heart
attack and not known?
It sounds like you did know but
you weren't diagnosed correctly.
Let's get her a stat echo.
How bad is this?
I'm gonna find out
what's going on.
What'd you
want to talk about?
In a nutshell. life is easier
when my ex-husband
and daughter are not at war.
Have you been doing
the breathing techniques
we worked on?
Let's do one together.
Come on.Okay.
Okay. In through the nose.
Out through the mouth.
Mm.
Mmm. See?
This...
is why I married you.
Okay. I have to go. Busy day.
Where. hopefully. I
won't run into Griff.
But if I do.
I will breathe.
And... Mm-hmm.
If that doesn't work.
try boundaries.
Those. I've got.
Had a feeling I might
find you out here. Isan.
Bereavement packet?
I have to return the
patient's things to the family.
Have them sign papers.
Hmm.
I don't know how to
explain what went wrong.
Didn't Anders already
talk to the family?
Yeah. I mean. for me.
I need to go over it again.
If I made a mistake.
I need to know.
so I can make sure it
never happens again.
Good luck.
Hi.
I have news. And an ask.
I scored a Whipple
later today.Oh.
Dr. Baum requested
me in general surgery
after I aced that
chole last week. Hmm.
I'm assuming the
request is to study for it?
If that's okay. I mean.
I could still be with you.
Mm. yeah. Absolutely.
Tell me how it goes?
Yeah. I will. Maybe
over a glass of wine later?
Uh... I'm not there yet.
I'm sorry. I'm trying.
And I really appreciate
you pushing me
to fight for this position.
but there's you. and
then there's my dad.
and then there's you
and my dad. and it's...
I really want for things to
get better between us. but...
But?
N-No. no. Butt.
Multiple butts. Oh.
Excuse me.
Hello?
Oh. uh. I've got to
get to another delivery.
but I set up the
first few for you.
What?
Uh...
Do you have any idea why
these were delivered here?
I didn't ask because
I didn't want to butt in.
- It wasn't funny the first time.
- Okay. sorry.
I-I didn't mean to be cheeky.
Dear God. make it stop.
You're right. No more cracks.
I think this is
the packing slip.
Thank you.
Uh. okay. they're
medical teaching tools.
used to hone
prostate exam skills.
This is the cardio
department. Why are they...
"Deliver to Dr. Sam Griffith."
Huh.
Huh. I don't suppose
you have any idea why
three dozen units
of nonrefundable
prostate equipment
were delivered here to me today?
My understanding is that these
are very advanced
training devices.
This is a prank.
and a very elaborate one.
So what is this really about?
Well. it's obviously a mistake.
But. well. it's
the kind of thing
that comes across the
chief's desk all the time.
You want me to make some calls?
No. I think you've done enough.
Okay. Well. either way. I win.
I know my dad. This
is more than just a joke.
I mean. is he trying
to distract me?
Maybe it's simpler than that.
Maybe he's just
trying to embarrass me
in front of everyone.
These are medical devices.
And we are all adults.
There is nothing
embarrassing here.
I... Dr. Griffith?
Mr. Kingsley.
Hello.
Thank you for taking
time out of your day.
I was looking for my son.
Is this...
the new tech you mentioned?
No. This is a mix-up.
A mix-up? I didn't order these.
I actually think
that my father did...
I've always said a good leader
takes responsibility
for everything
that happens on their watch.
I'm about to handle it.Great.
Let's talk when
you're done with that.
Mm-hmm.
Find me when you're free.
Of this.
Yes. sir.
Look. I know.
He's tough. but he is also fair.
He's open to a conversation.
He-He'll hear you out.
Except that his last memory
of me will be of the time
that I greeted him from
inside a sea of butts.
I have to get these out of here.
How did my dad
even get these in here?
I'm so sorry for your loss.
I don't understand.
People get
appendectomies all the time.
Every surgery carries risk.
The doctor last night said
that Dad hemorrhaged.
He didn't say why.
Do you know?
The reason isn't always clear.
But I'm gonna find one.
I promise.
Thank you.
Geez. what's wrong? Am I dying?
We're just concentrating.
It's probably nothing. Tracy.
They're just
being extra careful.
Stop right there.
Multiple wall motion
abnormalities.
Is that bad? That sounds bad.
Dr. Trulie. schedule a cath lab
and tag Joey in
so you can study.
Thank you.
So. the echo is telling us
that you didn't just
have one heart attack.
You've had many.
Tracy.
you might have felt pressure
in your chest or your arms.
Maybe you felt tired or dizzy.
Panic attacks.
Cardiac events.
Okay. Yeah. The
symptoms were mild enough
to be mistaken for...
Oh.No. Mm-mm.
Okay. hey.
Tracy. Tracy. Tracy.
Tracy. try to calm down.
Whoa. oh. Sick people
have heart attacks.
Old people have heart attacks.
No one in my family has
ever had a heart attack.
Tracy.
Tracy. Go prep the
cath lab. I got her.
Tracy. Tracy?
There's my son. working
so hard. he forgets to find me.
Or eat lunch.
I'm sorry.
The boss is in town.Mm-hmm.
Heard he was a hard-ass.
Only if he sees you
making a mistake.
Ooh. that is a record.
I haven't even opened
my sandwich yet.
I saw you
seem to have a personal
relationship with Sam Griffith.
I do.
It... I mean. it's... it's
new. but. uh. yeah.
I'm not trying to interfere
in that part of your life.
but we came up with
a plan for your career:
You climb till you succeed me.
Well. that will be a weird day.
That'll be a great day.
And I don't want
you getting distracted
or derailed on the way there.
Do you not like Sam?
I don't like her pulling you
into her family power struggle.
No. that... that's
not what she's doing.
Are you sure?
You led her straight to
me at the donor event.
And this morning
I found you right in
the middle of her mess.
Just looking out for you. son.
Worst Netflix and chill ever.
Doesn't matter how many times
I see it. how much I slow down
or freeze. I can't
tell what went wrong.
Well. you can't
control everything.
Yeah. "leave it up to the
universe. I can't control it"?
That's how guys like you
get by with no accountability.
Oh. why stop talking
on my account?
Go on. get it out of your
systems. "Lex and Griff."
"Griff and Lex." We
weren't talking about you.
Sorry. It's just.
everyone else is.
Oh. no. don't get
me wrong. we did.
when it first came out.
but we're over it.
I mean...
20 people have probably slept
with each other around here
since your news came out.
This isn't helping.
I'm asking the family
to approve an autopsy.
Did you rule
out a burst implant?
We did. but after we clean
out this vessel blockage.
we'll have a conversation
with her plastic surgeon.
Who is it? Is it her?
Please tell me so I can prepare.
Nobody's getting
ahead of me on this one.
Plastics is all me.
Plastics
is a waste of time.
Your fetish for
interdisciplinary medicine
is not relevant in this
case. Push the dye.
Is that what this is all about?
You're protesting
my interdisciplinary approach
by littering my surgical lounge
with prostate devices?
I have no idea what
you're talking about.
I'm sure you don't.
I don't see the blockage yet.
Well. there's all kinds of
blockages. aren't there?
Stubbornness. pride. ambition.
It takes many forms.
Ugh. give me a break.
The dye is all the way in.
Her coronary
arteries are clear.
How did she have
multiple heart attacks
with perfectly clear arteries?
I don't know. but if we
can't see what's wrong.
we can't fix it.
Let's get her to the ICU.
Okay. we know Tracy fainted.
but does she have a history
- of fainting?
- It's not in her charts.
Chest pain after sex.
Unclear if they're related.
And she had knee pain.
Yeah. that sounds more like
the kind of sex.
not the sex itself.
Doesn't explain
the heart attacks.
Transient spasm in the
large coronary artery?
That's a lot of spasms.
Maybe it's coronary
microvascular dysfunction.
Or maybe it's
a spontaneous tear
- in the artery.
- Maybe it was Professor Plum
in the library with the wrench.
It is her.
Bad enough you
had to call plastics in.
Did you have to call Rhonda?
Zip it. you pompous gasbag.
I pulled Dr. Glass
in because she
is the chief of plastics.
I also
did all of Tracy's
previous surgeries.
which were impeccable.
by the way.
Dr. Glass. uh. my
name is Joey Costa.
May I just say. I'm
such a fan of your work.
Are you gonna tell me
what's going on here. Jerry?
Um... y-yes.
The patient has
no family history
of cardiac events. yet
she's been having trouble...
Long pedal on
the right. I'm sorry?
Speed it up. I'm familiar
with her backstory.
Down to where
she lost her virginity
and when she smoked
her first cigarette.
The former... Behind a
Walgreens in Dearborn.
the latter... Bowie's
Glass Spider Tour.
The woman is a talker.
Oh. coming from you...
I started at Lakeshore
a glorious five weeks
before his overbearing
ass appeared.
He resents my
seniority. Always has.
1987. Hmm?
Bowie's Glass Spider
Tour was in 1987.
Right. If Tracy
is 40... Hmm.
She would have only
been six years old then.
She lied about her age.
She told you she was 40?
Why would anyone
lie about their age?
Asked no woman. ever.
Do know if she ever
found a boyfriend?
Yeah. online.
There's your answer.
Guys on dating apps. they're
interested in two numbers:
Your dress size and your age.
Either of them doesn't
meet with their approval.
they're swiping left.
This changes everything.
We have to run a
battery of new tests.
I mean. Tracy's real age
elevates her risk factors
for multiple conditions.
Well. she just made
it harder on herself
by not giving up the
game to start with.
Ah. She's trying
to win at a game
where the odds
are not in her favor.
I. for one. don't blame her.
- Hey. Sam.
- Hi.
I did some digging into how
Griff bought those devices.
All right. he still
has signing authority
on the Lakeshore account.
What? How?
Well. nobody ever revoked it.
All right. not
even after he fell into his coma.
N-No... Can you revoke
it now? Look. Sam.
I like where we are.
I do. too. Good.
It's just. I'm starting to find
my professional footing here.
And-and you and I
working together and
dating... look. it's complicated.
No. no. no. I-I'm not
saying I want to stop.
Okay? I don't.Good. Same.
It's just on this one.
I think you need to
bring it to your mom.
Oh.
Yeah. Okay.Yeah.
I will go talk to my mom.
I know. I know. I'm on it.
No more signing
authority for your father.
Why did he even still have it?
It was an oversight.
I didn't think about revoking it
because he barely ever used it.
Well. today he used it to
litter my department's lounge
with a bunch of
useless equipment
right when I am trying to prove
that I am a fiscally
responsible department head.
Okay. there. Done.
Listen. when your father and I
were building
Lakeshore. he wasn't part
of the financial
equation beyond donors.
I mean. he would schmooze
on the golf course. that's it.
I managed
all his paperwork.
I balanced his books. I
cleaned up his messes.
And that is how CT came to
be the powerhouse it is today.
I know. but now. it's a pow...
Now it is a powerhouse
with a balance
sheet full of butts.
I know.
It's brilliant.
You know. if I
say "My dad did it."
I look like I can't
control my personnel.
And if I say that I
didn't know about it.
I look like I'm clueless about
my own department's finances.
All right. let's look
up the contract.
Okay. Okay.
we're gonna fix this.
I already have a plan to
save $100K. which is a start.
How much were the devices?
What?
$2 million?!
Well. hello.
I thought I was the only one
who haunted the lab
waiting for test results.
I was
hoping to talk with you.
Much as I enjoy my ringside seat
to you and your
father's cage match.
you're never gonna beat him.
Not like this.
What do you mean?
You're gonna have to
get a whole lot dirtier.
I know where the
bodies are buried.
Why would you help me?
'Cause you're the
only Griffith I can stand.
You want my dad
out of the picture.
Don't you?
N-No. I-I'll pass.
This isn't about
digging up dirt. this
is about who's best
to lead the CT department.
Here's your results.
Thank you.
Tracy's estrogen is high.
Especially for
someone in menopause.
Or perimenopausal at least.
She must be taking
hormone replacement therapy.
Which could be prothrombotic.
We've got to get
her off the estrogen
and onto an anticoagulant.
Great.
Nice doing business with you.
Mm-hmm. If you ever want to do
any other business. you
know where to find me.
We could just
wait for pathology.
We're here now.
There are other
patients upstairs.
and they're alive.
Well. it's been a while
since I've done an autopsy.
I'm not as cavalier
as you might think.
If you need to do
this for peace of mind
or pride or whatever. I'll help.
It's not like a patient has
never died on my watch before.
It was Anders. the
way he looked at me.
When he called
the time of death...
Well. he was upset.
We were all upset.
It was regret.
- No. Isan. You're wrong.
- I'm not.
I've seen it in my dad's
eyes my whole life.
He's in family practice;
Thought I should be. too.
Not because he wants
me to be his partner;
No. because he doesn't think
I'm good enough to be a surgeon.
So. you have to prove you are.
Um... D-Do you want
to pass me the forceps?
What did you find?
No. nothing.
What?
I nicked the iliac.
That's why he bled out.
I killed him.
Isan?
Isan!
Do you need
something. Dr. Griffith?
Uh...
Yeah. sure.
Uh. so. my golf
clubs are up north.
And I would usually
send Isan to get them.
but he's not answering his
texts and I am playing tomorrow.
Ergo. I am in the market
for a shiny. new set.
Uh...
This thing is... keeps
giving me an error message.
- It's broken.
- It's not broken.
Your
payment was declined.
That's not possible.
It's a Lakeshore card.
Platinum.
It's not working.
Maybe just use a personal card.
That's a great
idea. You have one?
I meant. your personal card.
My personal
card. for a business expense.
Funny.
The packing slip says the
devices are nonrefundable
and I can't find a
loophole in this contract.
Is there anything
on the website?
No. there barely even is one.
The company must be new.
There's only a splash page.
Well. what about a phone number?
Yeah. the same one
we've already tried.
Nothing but automated
customer service.
Yeah. I can't tell a
recording that I need
a $2 million refund.
Breathe. and stay calm.
It'll defuse the
situation with Griff.
Thank you.
Vivian! I need you!
Griffith. You're looking well.
Pyne. You're looking
exactly the same.
I don't know what that means.
but knowing you.
it's probably an insult.
I always forget how your
generation is just so sensitive.
I never forget how yours is not.
What is wrong with my
Lakeshore credit card?
What a stupid question.
What do you...
It has been revoked.
And I need an explanation
for the $2 million
that you've spent.
Good lesson for Sam.
A lesson? Who orders
a bunch of stupid...
Why does he sound like he's
transitioning to active labor?
My new husband
has some techniques
to help me deal
with my old husband.
Oh. millennial
medicine. That's cute.
I find it helpful.
If you don't
want to do the breathing.
- try boundaries.
- Mm.
Have a serene afternoon.
Yeah.
God. you're a fool.
Oh... A shortsighted fool.
because even if you do
manage to get your old job back.
your department's gonna
have a $2 million deficit.
I can make it up on the course.
I've got a plan. Just involves
a new set of golf clubs.
No. you have money.
You buy your own club.
That doesn't make any sense.
They're a legitimate
business expense.
Besides. that limited
edition copper set I bought?
What. four grand
with the engraving?
It's seven years ago.
$2 million amortized over time.
that's less than a penny a club.
That is not what
"amortized" means.
I want those devices
returned and refunded.
All right. Vivi. I hear you.
I'm not in the business
of making anyone's
life more difficult.
Give this to Sam.
It's the sales rep
that I dealt with.
Th... What. this is an
actual. live person?
Bit of a dud. but he's alive.
He did the deal. I don't
know if he wants to undo it.
Nobody wants to
refund $2 million.
- We'll see about that.
- Thing is. there is a way
you could thank me for
giving you his number.
Still with the stupid clubs.
They're actually smart clubs.
They compensate for
hooks and slices... Fine.
Get back to work.
Hey.
Ready for the Whipple?
Please. don't. No.
no. no... Can I help?
Come on. What?
What... Hey.
It's a conversation.
It doesn't matter.
To you. You know.
it's different for me.
They see me as your
mistress first. doctor second.
That's not true.
You have no idea.
All right? It was
already hard enough
for me to be taken
seriously before.
Now I have to work double
just to get my credibility back.
Hello. everyone.
Thank you.Hey.
Thanks again for giving me
the time to study for this Whipple.
It's a lot.Mm-hmm.
Look. Sam. this is
harder than I thought.
It's like every time I'm
anywhere near Griff.
all people think about
is. you know. that.
Well. maybe you shouldn't
curl up on a bench with him
and whisper.
Sorry.
I'm still thinking
about it. too.
Tracy Reynolds is
having another heart attack.
What?
Push 150 of amio.
Push 70 of roc
and 20 of etomidate.
Do it.
7-0 tube to me.
Do you see that?
Look like lesions. Viral?
She's stable for now.
Let's get a sample of
this to the lab ASAP.
This might be what's
causing all her problems.
Are you gonna be okay?
Isn't your shift over?
I'm fine. You can go.
You don't look fine.
And that makes sense.
I mean. it's hard to
look at your mistakes.
Own up to them.
They call it a "fearless and
searching moral inventory."
- Who calls it that?
- People in recovery.
You know. like. accepting
the things you cannot change.
Do you really think
appropriating 12-step mottos
is gonna help me feel better?
It helps me feel better.
What do you mean?
I got sober a couple months ago.
right after Sam and I broke up.
I made a lot of mistakes.
And now I'm just trying to
do better one day at a time.
I had no idea.
I was good at hiding it.
Nobody knows yet. It's new.
I think if you can
accept that you did all
you could for this patient.
it'll be best for the
patients who still need you.
Prelim path is in.
Your guy had a malignant mass.
It's pretty advanced
appendiceal cancer.
His tissue was falling apart.
That's why the
sutures wouldn't hold.
Well. I still hit the iliac.
Yeah. but if he hadn't had
cancer. you could have fixed it.
I know that you don't
normally permit refunds.
but this is a unique
circumstance. Uh...
I'm not saying that the charge
was fraudulent. I'm just...
"Cause"? Oh. come on.
The cause is that no one needs
this many plastic butts. Bernie.
This is for Tracy Reynolds. Can
you put a rush on those. please?
Sir. I need you to
connect me to your boss.
Sir? Sir?
- Oh...
- Looks like it's gonna be a late night.
There's a Whipple in
the OR ahead of me.
Hope
they got a good assist.
Trulie. Which one is that?
The hot one. third year. braids.
Apparently she "assists" Griff.
Oh.
right. the Griff girl.
Explains
how she got the Whipple.
Oh. boy.
Oh. wow.
I know you were not insinuating
that a tremendously
talented surgeon
got into an operation for any
reason other than her skill.
No?
If I can get past Dr. Trulie's
recent personal choices.
you certainly can.
And the only thing
you need to think.
let alone say about her is
that she is an incredible doctor.
And if she got an opportunity
earlier in her career
than any of you.
that is on your lack of skills.
Not on her.
Hmm?
Labs got nothing.
It's not a virus.
Dr. Glass. can
you walk us through
all of Tracy's cosmetic
procedures. please?
Mm-hmm. Breast
augmentation. that was the start.
Lower rhytidectomy after that.
Blepharoplasty a year later.
Laser skin resurfacing. she
gets that done fairly often.
Where? Just her face?
Mostly. Few times on her legs.
Varicose vein removals.
How often did you do her veins?
More than most.
It's not Tracy's age.
It's a disease. She
was trying to smooth out
her skin but it
wasn't age spots.
Joint pain. She
said her knees hurt.
Arthritis. headaches.
oral lesions.
Superficial venous thrombosis.
Tracy has Behcet's syndrome.
Blood vessel
inflammation exacerbated
by the estrogen supplements.
None of which you caught
while doing every
procedure under the sun.
Oh. can it. Women get
work like this done every day.
You want me to screen them all
for rare autoimmune disorders?
She's right.
Damn right I'm right.
I didn't invent
beauty standards.
even though they
do pay my mortgage.
Standards.
Start her on a gram
of methylprednisolone.
That'll knock out the
inflammation for today.
And then we are
gonna get her a team
of specialists to
tailor her medications
to her specific
symptoms. I have to go.
Come on...
That won't get it
here any faster.
The devices.
They're for teaching. right?
The contract specifically says
that they represent a
"typical human body."
except they are
all the exact same.
They represent one body type.
and it is young. thin and white.
To call it "typical"
is biased and discriminatory.
And it implies that
there is a standard.
And that is a standard
that my patient
nearly killed herself
trying to live up to.
Which nobody wants to argue
in the court of public opinion.
Exactly!
Which is why
they are gonna let me
return all of those butts
for a full refund.
Hello.
Wow.
Boundaries.
I mean. deep down. he knew
what he was doing he was wrong.
He just needed to hear it in
language he could understand.
Now. of course. he
also needed a new set
of golf clubs. but...
That sounds like Griff.
You know. he just
handed over the information
Sam needed to
cancel the contracts.
Asher. it was just...
That sounds less like him.
Hey. Want to help me
pack up some butts?
Only a fool would say
no to that.
So. you called them and you
got them to give you a refund?
Yeah. that's what they say.
I'm still waiting on
the confirmation email.
Well. so might you say
you butt-dialed them?
No.
I-I really needed that.
Thank you.
You always made
me laugh so much.
I still could.
How's Isan?
Uh. he's... you know.
it's a tough day. but
he's on the other side of it.
Ugh. please. please. please.
Ha!
There's the email.
Butts refunded in full.
What is the company called?
Uh. I
think it Emoti-Med.
This says that the
$2 million refund
is coming from "The
Waxman Corporation."
Well. that's okay... it's
probably the parent company.
No. no. no.
Waxman?
Oh. my God.
Gerald Waxman.
Oh. Sam.
It was never about the devices.
I walked right into his trap.
Of course he didn't
care about the golf clubs.
He just needed you to think
that he wanted something.
that this was a trade.
Gerald Waxman. multimillionaire
entrepreneur and philanthropist.
Lakeshore's internal says
he's given a ton of donations.
Way more than the
two million his devices cost.
This month.
Waxman pledged to give
Lakeshore a new donation.
How much?
$12 million.
Waxie just called. Apparently.
he was counting on that sale
to raise the profile of
his new company. so...
when you canceled the
contract. he canceled the donation.
You let Lakeshore lose
an eight-figure donation?
And pinned it on me.
I did tell you that the
lesson was gonna hurt.
Hmm. But class is done.
We can put all this behind
us and move forward.
Here's what's gonna happen.
I'll go down to storage
where they boxed up
my stuff when I was shot
and unconscious
and you stole my job.
And somewhere
down there is a bottle
of 50-year-old single malt.
I'll take it to my office...
It's Sam's office.
You finish with your patients.
do what you have to do
and come to see me.
We'll have a drink.
and negotiate your surrender.
Thanks for sticking
around to chat.
Always.
Look. I respect what you said.
but I can't sit this one out.
I'm on Sam's side.
Not because she needs
me. but because she doesn't.
She is the better leader.
Sam Griffith just made a mistake
that cost Lakeshore
a lot of money.
And I am sorry to hear that.
but it doesn't change my mind.
She will find a
way to turn the tide.
You don't sound very neutral.
And you are?
Man. who are you kidding?
All this golf with Griff?
That's my business. son.
And Sam is mine.
Do what you want.
But I can tell you
from experience.
making alliances too
early in your career
can lead to disaster.
You are gonna
feel so much better
once the immune-modulating
medication
and the steroids kick in.
And your heart will
be healthier. too.
You must think I'm so stupid.
Tracy. I'm one of two
women in my department.
We're both battling how
we're perceived every day.
Baldwin left.
He said it wasn't my age.
it was the fact that I lied.
Can I offer you my
professional opinion?
You know. as a doctor?
Baldwin does not deserve you.
You're probably right.
But it's hard to find
someone. you know?
Someone you really gel with.
Yeah.
I'm sorry.
I'm gonna come check
on you later. okay?
Okay.
Hey.Hey.
How was the Whipple?
Slayed it. But that's
not why I'm here.
Thank you for what
you said earlier.
I know it's hardest for you
with the whole...
me and him thing.
When those idiots
were talking about you.
I wasn't thinking about that.
I was just thinking
about my friend.
The wine thing?
Let's do that sooner than later.
I would love that.
Me. too.
Shall we go tonight?
Mm. unfortunately.
tonight I have to...
drink with someone else.
Excuse me.
Are you Dr. Isan Shah?
I am. Can I help you?
You've been named in
a wrongful death lawsuit.
You've been served.
Tell me how to hit him.
Happy to.
But like I said...
my help comes with a price.
Rhonda. if it's less
than $12 million...
I'm in.
Captioned by Media Access
Group at WGBH access.wgbh.org
Watch Online Movies and Series for FREE
www.osdb.link/lm